# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hi guys! This is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我给大家分享
In today's video I'm gonna share with you
# 鱼腥草猪肺汤
Pig lung soup with fish mint
# 首先我们准备新鲜的猪肺1副
First we have a pair of fresh pig lungs
# 然后用水管对着气管灌入清水
And then pump in water through the trachea
# 灌满清水之后用牙签将其戳出小洞
When the lung is filled with water, use a toothpick to stab over the surface
# 这一步的目的是循环猪肺中的脏水
The purpose of this step is to discharge the dirty fluids from the lung
# 灌水满之后再倒出反复灌洗十遍以上
Pour out the water after the lung is full, and repeat this step over ten times
# 中途可以挤压猪肺让其快速循环
during which you can press the lung to speed up the water circulation
# 直到清洗为粉红色或者白肺为止
Until the lung appears pink or white
# 下一步开始初加工
Next, let's start the initial procedure
# 首先将猪肺气管上依附的淋巴取下
First, remove the lymph sticking to the trachea
# 淋巴不适合食用所以必须去除干净
The lymph is not edible. It must be completely removed
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next, let's get the minor ingredients ready
# 准备生姜2块拍散之后备用
Crush two lumps of ginger
# 准备小葱几根挽成结备
Tie up a few scallions for later use
# 下一步开始焯水
The next step is to parboil the lung
# 首先在锅中加入大半锅清水
Pour in more than half wok of water
# 然后加入准备好的姜葱
Drop in the ginger and scallion
# 将猪肺冷水下锅焯水10分钟
Put in the pig lung when the water is still cool, and parboil it for 10 minutes
# 这一步的目的是将猪肺定型
This is to fix the shape of the lung
# 中途加入适量的白酒（约15克）
Add some Bai Jiu (lit. Clear Chinese cooking wine)
# 大火烧开之后再撇去浮沫
Boil the water in high heat and then remove the scum
# 10分钟之后将猪肺捞出
After 10 minutes, take out the pig lung
# 然后将猪肺改刀切成小块
Cut the lung into small pieces
# 这一步的目的是让猪肺能够充分焯水
So that the lung can be parboiled thoroughly
# 将猪肺切好之后准备再次焯水
Prepare to parboil for the second time
# 然后锅中加入适量的清水
Pour in appropriate amount of water
# 将切好的猪肺下锅焯水10分钟
Parboil the lung pieces for another 10 minutes
# 中途继续加入适量的白酒去腥
Again, add some Bai Jiu to taste, in order to purge the smell
# 10分钟之后捞出
Take out the lung pieces after 10 minutes
# 捞出之后放入清水中清洗2遍
Wash them twice in clear water
# 这一步的目的是去除猪肺中间的脏东西
To remove the dirt within the lung
# 然后将猪肺切成小片备用
Furtherly cut the lung into small slices
# 切成小片之后加入食用盐1小把
After that, add a handful of salt
# 加入少许白醋
A little vinegar
# 然后抓洗5分钟备用
Grip and wash for 5 minutes
# 这一步的目的是去除异味
In order to remove the unpleasant smell and taste
# 5分钟之后加入清水投洗干净即可
After 5 minutes, rinse the lung slices in clear water
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next, prepare the side ingredients
# 准备生姜1小块拍散之后备用
Crush a small lump of ginger
# 准备折耳根200克备用
200g of fish mint for later use
# 下一步开始制作
Now let's start cooking
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
First, pour in appropriate amount of water
# 再加入处理好的猪肺下锅
Drop in the lung slices
# 中途加入几根小葱
During cooking, put in some scallions
# 大火烧开之后撇去浮沫
Bring to a boil over high heat and remove the scum
# 大火烧开之后转中小火煮90分钟
After boiling, turn down the fire and cook for 90 minutes in medium or low heat
# 这一步的目的是把汤熬至浓白
So that the soup could take on a white colour
# 煮至40分钟的时候捞出小葱再加入折耳根
After about 40 minutes, take out the scallions and put in the fish mint
# 90分钟之后开始调味
When the time reaches 90 minutes, start seasoning
# 锅中加入适量的食用盐（约8克）
Some salt to taste (about 8g)
# 加入1勺胡椒粉
A spoonful of pepper powder
# 调好味之后即可出锅
It is ready to serve after seasoning
# 一道营养丰富的猪肺汤就制作完成
Now this nutritious pig lung soup is finished
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，必须选择有检疫证明宰杀的生猪肺，如有黑斑或
# 大面积淤血的猪肺需谨慎
# 第二，猪肺必须反复灌水清洗，洗至粉色或者白色最佳
# 第三，折耳根猪肺汤具有一定预防呼吸道疾病的功效，同学们可以踊跃尝试
# 折耳根猪肺汤的技术总结完毕
Here are some tips:
Tip 1: Buy pig lungs from reputable, licensed butchers. Be cautious of lungs with black spots or lots of blood clots
Tip 2: The pig lung needs to be wash repeatedly until the colour turns pink or white
Tip 3: The pig lung soup with fish mint has some effect of preventing respiratory diseases. You might wanna have a try!
That's all for the tips